

SUMMARY

CTO, Solutions, Application and Data Architect and Engineer with extensive experience in planning, architecture, leading development and delivery of mobile and web SaaS and B2C applications, as well as mission critical enterprise solutions with in depth development background

SPECIALTIES

SaaS and B2C mobile and web,
Solutions Architecture and Applications
Delivery, Tech Stack/Data
Architecture, Business Intelligence,
Market Data Processing, Metadata,
Statistical Software, Reference Data
Management. Software Development
including architecture, design and
implementation of distributed, multi-tier
mobile and web software. Agile
software development methodologies
including SCRUM, test-driven software
development

CONTACT

PHONE: 917.345.5334

LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/leopelekh

EMAIL:

leopelekh@gmail.com

Leo Pelekh

Fractional/Full-time CTO. Solutions, Data Architect

CAREER ACCOMPLISHMENTS

As a CTO and Solutions Architect, record of rapid delivery of successful SaaS as well as large strategic enterprise solutions including:

Fractional/Full-time CTO, Application Architect, Development Lead

Defined, planned, architected, led development and delivery of variety
of successful SaaS and B2C mobile and web solutions

Principal Enterprise Application Architect at The Federal Reserve BankStrategic multi-year, multi million dollar Business Intelligence, Market
Data Capture and Analysis and Security Master

Enterprise Metadata Architect at Fannie Mae Strategic Enterprise Metadata Solution, ETL Solutions

EXPERIENCE

Fractional/Full-time CTO, Application and Data Architect May 2015–Current

Definined, planned, estimated, architected, lead implementation and delivery of SaaS applications for a variety of successful startup clients. Responsibilities included:

- Definition of technical strategy, plan and architecture
- Estimation and definition of high level project plan
- Sourced, interviewed, recruited and onboarded technical staff
- Implementation lead including DevOps, SaaS and Al integration
- Testing, monitoring and analytics
- Security, performance, scalability and reliability
- Application delivery
- Partner/vendor relations

Highlights include:

Rayse

Fractional CTO and Senior Architect

Jun 2023 - Jan 2023

Strategy, planning, architecture, technical team leadership, project estimation and delivery of this rapidly growing Real Estate sales cycle management Web and Mobile SaaS/B2C application including:

- Architect main product's software and back end infrastructure
- Plan development and build the technical team
- Drive requirements gathering
- Plan and lead project management
- Oversee DevOps including code reviews
- Consult on Lead Engineering tasks
- Administer and maintain Amazon AWS services

KitelyTech

Fractional CTO and Senior Architect

May 2022 - Jan 2022

Planning, technical team leadership, project estimation and delivery of Web and Mobile SaaS and B2C applications, including:

- Sales and Solutions Architecture and Engineering
- Discovery and Estimation
- Recruitment and Technical Leadership of development teams
- Project and Product Management

Fannie Mae

Enterprise Metadata Architect

February 2013-May 2015

Led a team of 20 engineers as an architect, designer, lead developer and evangelist of Fannie Mae's Metadata program. I implemented Metadata solutions that became the centerpiece of Fannie Mae's Enterprise Data program and had a significant impact during the US housing crisis.

Accomplishments:

Researched, evaluated, led proof of concept, designed and implemented an enterprise metadata tool including ETL, data scanners and GUI extensions. Designed Metadata Models, Data Lineage process and tools.

Technologies: Informatica Metadata Hub, Power Center, B2B Data Transformation Studio, Ab Initio Metadata Hub, Oracle RDBMS

Federal Reserve Bank of New York Principle Enterprise Applications Architect

October 2009–October 2013

Led a team of 30 – 40 engineers as an architect and tech lead on three successful multi-year strategic projects: Business Intelligence, Market Data Capture and Analysis and Security Master. Researched, evaluated, conducted proof of concept and led implementation by a team of SMEs. Designed security, availability, scalability, data integrity, monitoring, reporting, auditing, back up, archiving and disaster recovery. Delivery of these projects made a significant contribution to abatement of the US Financial Crisis of 2008.

Accomplishments:

Enterprise Business Intelligence Solution including permissioned analyses and metadata repository, governance processes, administrative auditing, RDBMS and Statistical Tool integration, delivered under estimate and budget

Time Series Data Management Solution including integration of real time and batch data feeds and integration with Business Intelligence Tool delivered under estimate and budget

Security Master Solution including access control and data deployment and promotion utilizing managed service model architecture delivered under estimate and budget

Technologies: Tibco Spotfire Suite, One Market Data OneTick, Broadridge, Golden Source Securities, Oracle 11G, Red Hat Linux Enterprise

Freelance Application Architect, Developer and CTO

November 2006-October 2009

Architected, designed and led development of web applications and software

Accomplishments:

Experiment control package for National Institute of Health. Employed Test Driven Development methodology with over 500 unit and integration tests with 90% code coverage. Delivered in 6 weeks with minimal defect rate

Real estate social network web application that combines aspects of social networking, user generated content and mobile technologies

Proposal Management SaaS used by some of the largest advertising firms

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, C#, F#, ASP.Net, MSSQL, MySQL

Lab 49

Lead Architect and Software Engineer November 2004–November 2006

Led teams, architected, designed and implemented solutions for large investment banking clients.

Accomplishments:

Securitized mortgage marketplace for top mortgage trading firms. Marketplace facilitated publication of securitized mortgage products information, product analysis and order placement and processing

P&L solution used by dozens of hedge fund clients for the Prime Brokerage department of top investment banks. The application facilitated calculation of profit and loss on equity positions and integration with risk management systems

OpenText

Principal Software Architect and Engineer

January 2001 - November 2004

Analyzed, architected, designed and coded the main offering -- a leading business process management solution used by 7 of 10 top Insurance, 16 of 20 top banks, and Social Security Administration

Accomplishments: Designed and implemented Goal Management Subsystem – a business analytics, beaconing, reporting and configuration automation facility

Designed and implemented Corporate Calendaring Subsystem – an analytics package that measured business process metrics

EDUCATION

New York University January 1998– November 2002 BS – Computer Science

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Venture with Impact

Humanitarian mission in Lima, Peru – technology, music education

Team Rubicon

Hurricane Disaster Recovery Wharton, Texas, Panama Beach Florida

HOBBIES

Music performance and production, blockchain applications. bicycle touring, mountain hiking